<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Scribbles</title>
<link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 20:21:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Past Lives</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-10-18 past lives.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>It feels as though the director made this movie just for me. I had to be at this point in my life to truly appreciate it. While my life isn’t as dramatic as the characters’, there is something about the immigrant experience that is so uniquely captured by the film.</p>
<p>Not too far into the movie, you realize that there cannot be any happy ending here. Every ending is going to be sorrowful in its own way - and isn’t that true about life itself? Yet you endure with patience, waiting for your chance to cry at an incomplete catharsis.</p>
<p>This could be one of the finest films I’ve ever watched.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kA244xewjcI?si=kDj2cn4DmYj6jirT" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="">
</iframe>



 ]]></description>
  <category>movies</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-10-18 past lives.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 20:21:12 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Smartless - Willem Dafoe</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-07 smartless willem dafoe.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>On one of my long drives recently, I was listening to the <a href="https://www.smartless.com/episodes/episode/22b8d8d5/willem-dafoe">Smartless episode</a> featuring <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Willem_Dafoe">Willem Dafoe</a>.</p>
<p>He shared a perspective that resonated with me. Although he’s American, he lives in Italy, making him an immigrant there. He mentioned that being an immigrant is a liberating experience for him, allowing him to see things from a distance, with an outsider’s perspective.</p>
<p>I’d never considered it, but it rings true for me as well. Being an immigrant in America, I have the unique vantage point to observe the absurdities, joys, and sorrows of this place, but from a distance. Having lived in another country gives me a completely different perspective, knowing how things could be elsewhere. I can never become too myopic here, as I never get too close to things. There is a sad yet liberating quality to it.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>podcast</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-07 smartless willem dafoe.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Board Games in Baltimore</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-04 boardgames.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>I have been trying out some board games groups around Baltimore. Sadly I could not find any in the city itself but I found quite a few in the surrounding areas. I have been to two events of far and already learned quite a few new games.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/339/quiddler">Quiddler</a></li>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/131357/coup">Coup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/262543/wavelength">Wavelength</a></li>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/158268/karma">Karma</a></li>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/258/fluxx">Fluxx</a></li>
<li><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/164840/monopoly-deal">Monopoly Deal</a></li>
</ul>
<p>They were all quick games and fun to play. If I were to buy any of these then it would be Wavelength. All the others were card games and fun to play with people who have never played board games before.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>boardgames</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-04 boardgames.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Harper’s Ferry</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-02 harpers ferry.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Over the last couple of years, I lived in Chicago and couldn’t go on hikes. The land there is flatter than a pancake. It’s a perfect place for long-distance biking but an extremely boring one for hiking.</p>
<p>I hiked the Loudon Heights trail at Harper’s Ferry and absolutely loved it. It was a bit tedious at first with no change in scenery - but that’s the whole point of hiking. It’s not about change, or being comfortable, or getting somewhere, but the journey itself. You walk for hours, letting your mind settle down and taking in the beauty of your surroundings. There’s a deep, ancient instinct that kicks in when you find yourself so close to nature. This feeling is hard to describe and equally hard to recollect.</p>
<p>When I hadn’t hiked for so long, I didn’t particularly miss it, but I was also slowly forgetting how much I liked it. It is a precious thing that I hope I don’t lose as I get busy with life.</p>
<p><img src="https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/https:/lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AIL4fc9bgv9JNXRvbNGbbvK-Ccwbeqxkei1OiNd0t0XEi1FaGDeFfl8CTWC7ihtJBSIpetKl2hdMdh8FD8HWUnD6cm3M7zBzAPUJgwu0WxQQfI0ZuQrgrjIRTDSvV8-Mvo_XA8s6uozQ71gV1DCTAerBc8oK7A=w825-h1096-s-no"></p>
<p><img src="https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/https:/lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AIL4fc_f62wmj53nRyC2b1p7lii4jNNtY4Y7w-Og7KQtt8jjXTXHNpWyW_5B6A27VsNhkLpruR7K3cX50-PEJzXDc3uecYraSQS_GrRjnH3p2JTU3MAJ6lpaIMBL1O8NAQDkLRednaSLGkz8flHWp90y4EHlSA=w825-h1096-s-no"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>journal</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-09-02 harpers ferry.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Group Exercise</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-30 group exercise.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>I like to think that I am generally a very fit person. I exercise almost everyday and generally lead an active life. Just for fun, I recently tried a Yoga Sculpt class and it kicked my ass.</p>
<p>This made me realize two things:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>When working out alone, it’s easy to not be fully honest with oneself. I probably take longer breaks, get sidetracked by my phone, or choose lighter weights when I could handle heavier ones.</li>
<li>We can often push ourselves more than we think. I never knew an hour-long HIIT session with weights, like Yoga Sculpt, was something I could do. I’m surprised I hadn’t tried it earlier.</li>
</ol>
<p>I once tried a yoga class via livestream, but it didn’t feel the same. The poses might have been identical, but the intensity was different.</p>
<p>I’ve started to see the benefits of group classes. They push you harder and offer new experiences you might not encounter otherwise.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>journal</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-30 group exercise.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chandrayaan-3</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-23 chandrayaan 3.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>India landed Chandrayaan-3 on the Moon! Amazing!!!</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gvj3w59EaFM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="">
</iframe>
<p><img src="https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/https:/media.tenor.com/XUAONVsG6qIAAAAC/leonardo-dicaprio-clapping.gif" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>journal</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-23 chandrayaan 3.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 18:45:49 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Starting Your Day Right</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-23 starting your day right.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>There is a strong correlation between my daily habits and my level of productivity. When I’m at my peak performance, everything feels automated and flowing.</p>
<p>In the past month, I relocated to Baltimore. Prior to that, I was frequently on the move, both for work and family commitments. As a result of which, my routine has been completely upended, and my habits are in complete disarray.</p>
<p>I came across this <a href="https://dailystoic.com/marcus-aurelius-daily-habits/">post on Stoicism</a> (something I greatly admire) which, among other things, talks about starting your day right. This made me realize how I’ve been swept up by the unproductive habit of checking my phone first thing in the morning.</p>
<p>Fortunately, I’ve just finished assembling my writing desk by a lovely corner window. My coffee is brewing and my trusty iPad is charged. Time to get back to morning journaling again. Hopefully, even when life gets busy and chaotic, I’ll have the stamina and discipline to keep up with this incredibly useful habit.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/images/writingDesk.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">My writing desk</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>stoicism</category>
  <category>habits</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-23 starting your day right.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Begin Again</title>
  <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-20 begin again.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>I’ve been blogging for as long as I can remember, starting from the early days of Blogger, Wordpress, and Tumblr, to the newer self-hosted realms of Github, Jekyll, and Hugo. Now that I’m entering a new phase of my life at JHU, here I am once again. I plan to write about the topics that currently occupy my thoughts: math, <s>teaching</s> learning, Lean, programming, philosophy of mind, books, movies, and more…</p>
<p>For me, writing serves as a way to clarify my thoughts while staying honest and consistent. As the wise Feynman once said “<em>The first principle is not to fool yourself – and you are the easiest person to fool.</em>” Expressing your thoughts and putting them out in the world (for nobody to read) is the first step towards that.</p>
<p>The title of this post is a meditation prompt by Sam Harris. I’m serious about practicing meditation and mindfulness, but regrettably, not very good at it. Whenever I catch myself doing something I would rather not (like procrastinating writing), I just remind myself to <em>Begin Again</em>.</p>
<p>So here’s to not fooling yourself and to new beginnings.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>journal</category>
  <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/scribbles/posts/2023-08-20 begin again.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 15:03:47 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
